hey guys rexin here welcome to another
crash course video this time on learning
how to play carota so let's get straight
into it kota's basic attack has five uh
sequences to it the first two hit is
from a pistol the second hit will give
her three crystals and these three
crystals can be converted into rifle
shots three hits of rifle shots so one
two three notice how when you spend
crystals it will build towards her gauge
so each Crystal spend will give her 10
points the gauge can hold up to 120
points the other ways to get her crystal
is simply pressing basic attack after
plunging so plunge basic attack three
crystals like this another way is also
to pressent whole basic to do her heavy
attack three crystals as well and
followed by intro attack also giving her
three crystals and also Dodge attack so
Dodge counter also gives her three
crystals really easy to build her forte
gauge note that the crystals only stay
for a while so be sure to spend them as
soon as you get them and that's pretty
much it for her basic attack now I will
talk about her resonance skill resonance
skill is really simple there's two parts
to a resonance skill the first part will
freeze the enemy for 1.5 seconds
including bosses and will also give her
three crystals like
so and then you simply press resonance
skill one more time to spend the three
crystals and follow up with a gap
closer like this straight away 30 points
and now what happens when the four Forte
gauge is full all you need to know is
whenever you do her forte attack it's
going to reduce the cool down of her
resonance skill by 6 seconds so
something to take note of you can always
use resonance skill first and then
followed by Forte so that you can spam
it let me show you I'll use resonance
skill
now 30 seconds cool down now pressing
whole basic for
Forte see how the cool down is reduced
so that Forte you saw was the enhanced
version because it had the red Crystal
over here and that red Crystal's cool
down is 22 seconds so if you do a full
Forte again without the red Crystal it's
going to be a weaker version of it but
it's still going to reduce the cool down
of a resonance skill by 6 seconds so
either Forte will reduce resonance skill
by 6 seconds and then if the crystal is
not there and you do Forte attack it's
simply going to look like
this just like that pretty low damage
but it still gets the job done on
reducing your resonance skill it's
really situational pay attention to the
cool of 22 seconds if you wanted to be
the enhanced version of the Forte and
that's pretty much it on how to play
carota and her forte just uh spend her
crystals into rifle shots rifle shots
will give uh Gage into her forte
including uh resonance skill second
button of resonance skill also gives
three crystals straight away Dodge
counter intro spend them all into rifle
shots and then once the Forte gauge is
full press and hold basic also reducing
the cool down of a resonance skill and
then you can use resonance skill again
like this and then rinse and repeat
another thing to note for carota is that
her rifle shots is capable of parrying
that's right so right now she is the
first pistol character that can Parry
attacks with a rifle so only rifle with
the that consumes the crystal this one
these attacks these can
Parry her e skill can Parry as well like
so if you hit an incoming Parry like
this it's going to Parry
another thing to note about Cara is that
she does not have aiming mode like the
traditional pistol user so if you press
G nothing will happen if you press an
whole basic attack it's going to be her
heavy attacks like
so so no more aiming mode we have to
gadget for that as for resonance
Liberation it's really simple all you
need to do is activate it and then spam
basic all the way and she'll finish it
on her own so press
ultimate spam basic four shots of basic
one two 2 3 4 and one more
time the only thing you can take note of
is that during the four shots of the
ultimate you can steer her Direction
simply by holding the movement stick
into the direction that she you want her
to slide to so when I press ultimate and
I'm just going to hold left all the way
hold left and
shoot like
this so you can slightly control car's
movement during the four shots maybe
away from the enemy while she's shooting
or to the side or to the front now let's
talk a bit about her technicalities so
for her weapon obviously her signature
weapon is the best it comes with crit
damage and increases attack by 12% and
every time she does an intro or ultimate
resonance skill damage bonus is
increased by 48% so this is already the
hint for you carota scales fully from
resonance skill similar to changli or
jiny all in on resonance skill of course
the other budget option for it will be
static Miss if you already have it as
for her Echo set the new set Frosty
resolve is tailored for her increases
resonance skill damage on the two set
effect and for the five set effect
casting ultimate gives her glacial
damage and resonance skill damage and
for the substats it's the usual for the
four cost it's going to be Sentry
construct the new boss crit rate or crit
damage depending on the weapon you're
using just balance your crit for the sub
stats the usual double crit double
attack resonance skill energy and for
the three cost double glacial or glacial
attack depending on what you have and
for the one cause it's going to be
attack of course since this set is still
new you can still use the old set
freezing Frost set while you build for
Frosty resolve as for a skill leveling
priority you want to go resonance
Liberation first and then followed by
Forte and resonance skill both of these
are equally important and Then followed
by normal attack and then intro skill
for the first inherent skill carota
gains a invincibility when she does a
plch attack after the second resonance
skill and also this the flight stamina
cost is reduced by 20% as long as she's
in the team te so that's a quality of
life simply for owning carota and for
the second inherent skill intro skill
resonance skill and resonance Liberation
death nail and heavy attack will give
deconstruction so what deconstruction is
is that she will place a debuff on the
enemy where any attacks will ignore 18%
of their defense for 4 seconds this
debuff initially only comes with the
first hit of her ultimate but by
leveling the second inherent skill it's
going to come with all this so resonance
Liberation death nail refers to the four
shots of ultimate after the first shot
and of course for the rest of the stat
bonus you want to level them all because
she comes with crit rate and also attack
percent as for her sequences carot is
already playable at s0 S1 gives her
additional crit rate when she applies
deconstruction on the enemy
deconstruction is the debuff when she
does her first ultimate or inherent
skill two and the second part of S1 is
that she gets 30 points of substance
after doing the second resonance skill
so that's a quality of life change that
lets her finish her rotation sooner as
S2 increases the final shot of her
ultimate by 1 to 6% so S1 and S2 is
already pretty Peak S3 adds an
additional 1,000% to outro as well as
93% to a resonance skill and S4 is a
team white buff so after doing her heavy
attack Forte the whole team gets 25%
resonance skill bonus S5 increases her
tinted Crystal Forte by 47% and S6 is a
direct Improvement to death Nell death
Nell refers to the four shots during her
ultimate just the four shots so 186%
increase in the whole damage and also
death nail shots will freeze the enemy
just like her resonance skill so each
shot will freeze them for 1.5 seconds so
just like all main DPSS more sequences
just means more damage you can settle
for szo if you want for kalota s0 and
her rank one weapon is already good
enough team composition why since Kota
is a DPS so she will always be the third
the usual the first character that you
bring in would be the healer either
Verina or short keeper and then Dudu
would be really for Kota since tutu
Buffs everything about her glacio
Amplified and also resonance skill and
then Kota kota's outro is just pure
damage you can still use moonlit Cloud
set for judu to buff kod or if your judu
is stacked with lots of coordinated
attack you can use the new imperian
Anthem it gives less damage boost to the
next character but it will dramatically
increase the coordinated attack damage
if you don't have tuu to buff Cara you
can also use Lumi if you have her or
even tchi that's pretty much it for Kala
it's really simple since she's just a
main DPS so an example rotation will
look like this you first you start with
your healer and then you switch in
either your Lumi or touchi or switch in
get their outro out and then you switch
to carot and you straight away use her e
skill both e
skills so since I have S1 she already
gets a extra 30 gauge and then all you
need to do is do another three shots to
be able to do her full
Forte like
that and that's pretty much it for the
crash course hope it's been helpful to
you and understanding how to play carota
enjoy 2.0 and I'll see you in the next
video bye-bye